technologiebeaumont.com 2016-11-01

# Wajam.com | Privacy

## Privacy Policy – Wajam

NEW

Effective Date: 01 May, 2016

### Introduction

This privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") is designed to make important and transparent disclosures about how we collect, share and use our users' information. Our users' privacy is important to us. We encourage you to read the Privacy Policy carefully and use it to make informed decisions.

This Privacy Policy governs the data collection practices by Wajam Internet Technology Inc. ("Wajam", "us", "we" and "our") while you use our (i) www.http://technologiebeaumont.com.com site; OR (ii) browser extensions; OR (iii) our software product (if applicable) (collectively "Wajam Products").

By using the Wajam Products you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of the Wajam Products constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is part of our [End User License Agreement](http://technologiebeaumont.com/terms-of-service) and the definitions herein shall have the same meaning as defined in the [End User License Agreement](http://technologiebeaumont.com/terms-of-service). If you do not agree to these terms, please do not access or use the Wajam Products.

### TRUSTe

**TRUSTe Privacy Seal.** [ ](http://privacy.truste.com/privacy-seal/Wajam-Inc-/validation?rid=f1940960-6a7a-4b5a-a313-822cc7bd9902 "TRUSTe online privacy certification") The TRUSTe Program covers only information that is collected through the English version of this Web site, technologiebeaumont.com. In order to view our relationship with TRUSTe please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe seal. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request. 

**TRUSTe Trusted Download Program.** [ ](http://clicktoverify.truste.com/pvr.php?page=validate&softwareProgramId=213&sealid=112 "TRUSTe Trusted Download Certification") The Wajam software version 1.0 has been certified by the TRUSTe's Trusted Download Program signifying that the Wajam software has been tested TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's TDP program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding the Wajam software, please contact us at: Wajam 4115 St-Laurent Suite 300, Montreal, Quebec, H2W 1Y7, Canada or by email at: [feedback@wajam.com](mailto:feedback@wajam.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe [here](http://clicktoverify.truste.com/pvr.php?page=validate&softwareProgramId=213&sealid=112). The TRUSTe Trusted Download program does not cover other applications such as the Twitter application. 

### What Information We Collect?

We collect two types of data and information from our users. 

#### (i) Non-Personal Information

The first type of information is un-identified and non-identifiable information pertaining to a user(s), which may be made available or gathered via the user's use of the Service ("Non-Personal Information"). We are not aware of the identity of the User from which the Non-personal Information was collected.

Non-Personal Information which is being collected includes the user's aggregated usage information and technical information transmitted by the user's device, including certain software and hardware information about the user's device (e.g. the type of browser and operating system) all in order to provide our Service as defined and detailed in the [End User License Agreement](http://technologiebeaumont.com/terms-of-service).

We collect the following Non-Personal Information from you when you install or use the Wajam Products and Service:

  * The type of device, operating system and browsers you are use;
  * Internet service provider (ISP);
  * Date and time stamp as well as language preference;
  * Browsing usage including, URLs of the pages, clickstream data or referring/exit pages;
  * Whether you are accessing the Website or use the Wajam Products;
  * your IP address which under some regulations is concederd "Personal Information" (as defined below);
  * We might also collect a list of all add-ons you've installed to Firefox, Chrome and Internet Explorer in order to detect and solve add-on compatibility issues, if applicable;
  * We might require the list of installed programs, if and when applicable, in order to prevent fraud or any type of silent installations by distributors;

We may disclose, share or sell to third parties this Non-Personally Identifiable collected information as specifies below and solely if applicable.

Wajam will also collect search engine logs data to improve your search results and to maintain the security of our systems. Analyzing logs data helps our engineers improve the relevancy of your social search results. Search engine logs are anonymized and do not contain any personal information.

#### (ii) Personal Information

The second type of information is individually identifiable information, namely information that identifies an individual or may with reasonable effort identify an individual ("Personal Information").

We collect the following Personal Information from you when you install or use the Wajam Products and Service:

  * Publicly available information available on social networks (such as Facebook, Twitter or Instagram) as well other public sources. 
  * You may allow us to collect information from third-party social networks and websites (such as your social media profiles, for example Twitter). You can log in to our Website and the Wajam Products using sign-in services such as Twitter. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form.
  * The Service requires your login credentials for each third-party social network or website you would like to access through the Service. By providing your login credentials to the Service, you expressly request and authorize the Service to automatically login to these third-party social networks and websites as your agent, for the purpose of aggregating content which you are authorized to access.  
You control the Personal Information collected through the social networks, we collect solely what you decide to make available to us either directly or through our social networking partners. If you wish to update what information is shared through our social networking partner you can make the appropriate changes within the privacy controls of your social networking account. Should you terminate your use of the Service or remove and uninstall the Wajam Product, this information will be deleted within a reasonable period of time following the termination. Your third-party login credentials are hashed and stored with the strictest security standards.
  * We also collect information you provide voluntarily when contacting us, this information includes your name and email address and can be deleted at any time upon you request as specified herein.
  * We will not knowingly collect Personal Information of children.

### How Is The Data Used?

Our Service uses Personal Information for the following purposes:

  * To send periodic email communications relating to our Service or the Wajam Product, and customer care correspondence;
  * To improve our Service and maintain its integrity (for example to detect and prevent fraud).

We also use Non-Personal Information, aggregated information or statistics regarding user behavior as a measure of interest in, and use of, the Service or the Wajam Product in the form of aggregated data, such as overall patterns or demographic reports, which do not describe or identify any individual user.

### Sharing User data

We do not share the Personal Information with any of our partners, we may disclose Personal Information, or any information you submitted if we have a good faith belief that disclosure of such information is helpful or reasonably necessary to: (i) comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request; (ii) enforce our policies (including our Agreement), including investigations of potential violations thereof; (iii) investigate, detect, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities or other wrongdoing, suspected fraud or security issues; (iv) to establish or exercise our rights to defend against legal claims; (v) prevent harm to the rights, property or safety of us, our users, yourself or any third party; or (vi) for the purpose of collaborating with law enforcement agencies and/or in case we find it necessary in order to enforce intellectual property or other legal rights.

The Non-Personal Information may be used or shared in any of the above circumstances, as well as for the purpose of providing and improving our Services, marketing and advertising purposes and conduct business and marketing analysis, and enhance your experience. If we combine Personal Information with Non-Personal Information, the combined information will be treated as Personal Information for as long as it remains combined.

Information relating to aggregate statistics may be collected through the use of third-party cookies and other third party tracking devices.

We may share your Personal Information and Non-Personal Information, with our parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively "Affiliated Companies"). We may share Information, including Personal Information, in the event of a corporate transaction (e.g. sale of a substantial part of our business, merger, consolidation or asset sale). In the event of the above, our affiliated companies or acquiring company will assume the rights and obligations as described in this Privacy Policy.

### Cookies

When you use our Service or the Wajam Product, we will store cookies on your computer in order to facilitate and customize your use of our Service. A cookie is a small data text file, which a website stores on your computer's hard drive (if your web browser permits) that can later be retrieved to identify you to us. Our cookies may store information such as but not limited to the country where you are located. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, but some parts of our Service may not work properly in that case. We use cookies to provide you with customized content and to keep track of preferences you specify while you are using our Services; in addition we might use the cookies to assist in identifying possible fraudulent activities.

### Other Tracking Technologies

We also gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date and time stamp or clickstream data. We do link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you. Some of our business partners (e.g., Google Analytics, Third Party Advertisers, etc.) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Wajam only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third-party.

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by third parties on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store cookies, beacons, scripts and pixels. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on the Wajam Products or to display advertising based upon your web-browsing activity. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash cookies, please click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

### Third party collection of information

Our policy only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. To the extent that you disclose your information to other parties on our system or other sites throughout the internet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control, or to individuals whom we do not employ or manage, including any of the third parties to which we may disclose information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

The Service may also enable you to interact (whether directly or through link) with third party websites and services that are not owned or controlled by us ("Third Party Services"). We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any Third Party Services. Please be aware that the Third Party Services may collect Personal Information from you. Accordingly, we encourage you to read the terms and conditions and privacy policy of each Third Party Services that you choose to use or interact with.

### Advertising

You may view and manage your advertising preferences at any time by accessing your account settings available by clicking on the icons via the Wajam ads widget. You can choose to opt out of advertising at any time by visiting your account settings. We partner with a third party to either display advertising on the Wajam Product. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking here. Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. As long as your browser retains the Wajam opt-out cookie, Wajam won't serve ads to your browser.

### User Rights

We may rectify, replenish or remove incomplete or inaccurate information, at any time, provided that we have reason to believe that the information is not accurate or up to date, by emailing us at: [support@wajam.com](mailto:support@wajam.com). If you have registered to our services through social network or platform account, you may also manage what information you decide to disclose by changing your privacy settings on such platform.

PLEASE NOTE THAT UNLESS YOU INSTRUCT US OTHERWISE WE RETAIN THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT FOR AS LONG AS NEEDED TO PROVIDE THE SERVICES AND TO COMPLY WITH OUR LEGAL OBLIGATIONS, RESOLVE DISPUTES AND ENFORCE OUR AGREEMENTS.

### How do we safeguard your information?

Wajam makes best efforts to use security methods and encryptions when handling sensitive data (i.e., handle the user data securely, including transmitting it via modern cryptography);

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Personal Information, you acknowledge that: (a) there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control; (b) the security, integrity and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through the Wajam Products cannot be guaranteed; and (c) any such information and data may be viewed or tampered with in transit by a third party.

WE CANNOT GUARANTEE THE PRIVACY OR SECURITY INFORMATION OF THIRD PARTIES, SUCH AS FACEBOOK, TWITTER, AND INSTAGRAM. YOU ACKNOWLEDGE, UNDERSTAND, AND ACCEPT THAT THE COMPANY IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY BREACH OR EXPOSURE OF PRIVACY OR SECURITY RELATED TO THESE OTHER SITES OR SERVICES, AND YOU DISCLAIM US FROM ANY AND ALL LIABILITY RELATED TO SUCH BREACH OR EXPOSURE.

### Minors

We forbid users under the age of 18 to use our Service. If you are under 18, please be sure to read this policy with your parents or legal guardians and ask questions about things you do not understand. Children under 13 (U13) are prohibited from using the Services provided by Wajam. In the event that we become aware that a user under the age of 18 has shared any information, we will discard such information. If you have any reason to believe that a child under the age of 18 has shared any information with us, please contact us at: [support@wajam.com](mailto:support@wajam.com).

### Blogs

As a registered user, you may post, submit and exchange content and information on areas of the Website that are accessible to other users (such as our blog page) if you decide so. You should exercise caution if you choose to disclose Personal Information in a publicly accessible area. You are solely responsible for any Personal Information that you disclose and disseminate on publicly accessible areas. To request removal of your Personal Information from these areas of our Website, contact us at [privacy@wajam.com](mailto:privacy@wajam.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### Updates or Amendments to the Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to periodically amend or revise the Privacy Policy; material changes will be effective immediately upon the display of the revised Privacy Policy. The last revision will be reflected in the "Last modified" heading. Your continued use of the Service, following the notification of such amendments on our website, constitutes your acknowledgement and consent of such amendments to the Privacy Policy and your agreement to be bound by the terms of such amendments.

### How to contact us

you may contact us at Wajam 4115 St-Laurent Suite 300, Montreal, Quebec, H2W 1Y7, Canada or by email at: [feedback@wajam.com](mailto:feedback@wajam.com). Instructions on how to uninstall Wajam can be found at our [How to Uninstall Wajam](http://technologiebeaumont.com/howto/uninstall) page. If you need any additional information, you may contact us at [support@wajam.com](mailto:support@wajam.com).
